Finding Aid for Michigan State Federation of Women’s Clubs records, 1896-1957
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan State Federation of Women’s Clubs records 1896-1957
Michigan State Federation of Women’s Clubs.
1 linear foot
851874 Bk.W 2
State-wide organization ccordinating some acitvites of local Women's Club; records include correspondence, reports and minutes of meetings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of Mrs. George Hunter (donor no. 3371 ) and came to the library in 1959.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In 1895, delegates from local women's clubs from throughout the state met in an organization convention to form the Michigan State Federation of Women's Clubs. The purpose of the organization then was to cooperate on those issues which were common to most of the state's women's clubs and to provide guidance to newly formed local groups.
The records of the organization relate primarily to the formative years of the Federation, the late 1890s to approximately 1920. Included are secretary's records and reports, correspondence, and committee materials.
Subjects:
Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; Michigan State Federation of Women's Clubs.
- Organizational records
  - Papers, undated and 1896-1957, 18 folders (Box 1)
  - Corresponding Secretary's Reports, 1899-1904 (Box 1)
  - Corresponding Secretary's Reports, 1905-1914 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Education Reports, 1898-1905 (Box 1)
  - Legislative Committee Reports, 1898-1905 (Box 1)
  - Board of Managers Reports, 1898-1907 (Box 1)
  - Recording Secretary's Reports, 1898-1903 (Box 1)
  - Badge Pin Committee Reports, 1899-1907 (Box 1)
  - Lucinda H. Stone Memorial Scholarship, 1904-1908 (Box 1)
  - State Convention Registration Lists, 1901-1911 (Box 1)
  - Fifty Year History of the club, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Notebook: include minutes and annual reports, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
  - Record book of the Corresponding Secretary, 1896-1899 (Box 1)
  - Record book containing memoranda of correspondence and disposition of material, 1910-1914 (Box 1)
  - Record book containing memoranda of correspondence and disposition of material, 1914-1926 (Box 1)
  - Record book of papers and materials loaned, 1916-1921 (Box 1)
  - Record book of material and correspondence received, 1914-1919 (Box 1)